DAN KLEIN: So we've just talked
about what a CSP is.
We've seen various kinds of CSPs and how
to formulate them, and now we're
going to talk about methods
for solving them.
The first thing you might think of is,
well, it's a sub case of search.
Let's just use search.
And there is a standard way of solving
CSPs with search that is going to be
the primary method we solve them.
So in the standard search formulation,
we still have states.
We still goal tests and so on.
What are the states?
The states are defined by the values
that are assigned so far, and that
means a state is a partial assignment.
The initial state in the search problem
is the empty assignment, where
no values have been assigned
to any variables.
The successor function for a given
partial assignment assigns a value to
a single unassigned variable,
so it extends that
assignment by one variable.
And the goal test is, is the current
assignment complete?
That is, do all variables have
values assigned to them?
And are all constraints satisfied?
So if we do, this will be our first
straightforward approach.
It's not going to work very well
by itself, but we'll improve it
incrementally.
So let's test and make sure we
understand this search problem.
So here's the case of Australia
shown in the applet.
I'm going to show you a different graph
in a demo, but first let's think
for the case of Australia.
What would breadth first search do?
Let's think about it.
What's at the root of the tree?
The root of the tree is some state,
which is nothing assigned.
What are the children of that state?
Right.
They're all single assignments, right?
Each of these has one assignment,
like V equals red.
Right.
And there's a bunch of them.
And the children of V equals red are
a bunch of other assignments, which
include V equals red and one more.
What's breadth first search
going to do in this tree?
It's going to try the top layer.
And then the second layer.
Is it going to find anything
the second layer?
No.
It's going to try the third layer,
and the fourth layer.
And where are all the solutions?
They're all at the bottom.
Breadth first search stays up at night,
kind of worrying about cases
like this, where the solutions are all
at the bottom, meaning it has to
search the entire tree before it even
has a chance of finding that last
layer with the solutions in it.
All right, so breadth first search
is kind of in trouble here.
It's kind of the worst possible
case for breadth first search.
So, what would depth first search do?
Starts at the top, right?
Empty assignment.
It goes down.
It assigns something.
From there, it's going to take that
deeper assignment, and assign
something else, and then something
else, and something else.
And it's going to zip straight down
the tree, and it's going to very
quickly find a complete assignment.
Now, who knows whether that assignment's
in fact going to pass the
goal test, right?
It may not actually satisfy
the constraints.
But at least depth first search is
making an effort towards getting where
the solutions are.
So we mocked depth first search in the
last unit, but now suddenly we're
seeing why we cover it at all.
In the case where all the solutions are
at the bottom, and you're going to
spend most of your time managing that,
depth first search is a great choice.
So let's see depth first search, this
wonderful choice in action.
Again, this is a map coloring case.
So right now this is the empty
assignment, and in depth first search,
we're going to start assigning
one variable.
And then the next, and then the next,
according to our exploration strategy.
And so what gets assigned first?
Well, let's say we start
in the lower left.
So first we would assign,
for example, blue.
Now, remember in depth first search,
there are still other options that are
on the stack, or on the fringe.
But this is the one we're going
to recurse into first.
All right, so what do we assign next?
Well, let's say it's the middle
one on the bottom.
And what will we assign it?
Well, you know, we're going to call the
successor function, and behold,
we'll assign it blue.
OK.
What happens next?
You think, oh, maybe we backtrack.
Wrong.
Right.
What happens in depth first search is
you call the successor function.
And guess who has successors?
Successors.
And so, depth first search is going
to all the way to the end.
It's going to realize this doesn't
have any successors.
It's going to pull the next thing off,
and then the next thing, and then the
next thing.
And so you can keep this up.
I'll speed this thing up, and
it's going to kind of
explore a bunch of stuff.
And you know, depth first search is
going to spend a lot of time.
And in some sense, this is all
just wasted, because when
did it make its mistake?
Like instantly, right?
So depth first research is going
to spend a lot of time.
I'm not even going to
let this continue.
So that's that.
OK, so something's wrong here.
There's actually a couple
things wrong here.
And let's fix it.
So for naive search, there's actually a
couple problems we're going to have
to fix before we're even going to have
a hope of applying this to any
reasonable problem.